What?
怎么
You don't remember me already?
这么快就不记得我了
Chen Huo'e?
陈火蛾
I don't care who you are,
我不管你是谁假扮的
playing these tricks here.
在这儿装神弄鬼
I suggest you
本阁领建议你
hand over the antidote
在我动手之前
before I get violent.
先把解药给我
Otherwise, I have no problem
要不然我不介意
killing Chen Huo'e again.
再杀一次陈火蛾
Anyone who's crossed swords
任何人只要与本阁领
with me,
交过一次手
no matter how long ago,
不管过去多久
I'll recognize them.
我都能认得出来
Chen Huo'e and I fought many times,
陈火蛾与我交手数次
so no matter
所以不管你
how hard you try
怎么努力隐藏
to hide your style,
自己的交手痕迹
it's pointless.
都是徒劳
A fake is always a fake.
假的永远都是假的
Too bad
只可惜
there's only one vial of antidote.
这解药只有一瓶
Are you brave enough
不知道沈大阁领
to take it?
敢不敢来拿
You're really
沈大阁领
willing to risk your own life
还真是为了百姓
for those people.
连自己的性命都不顾
As for those worthless commoners,
那些贱民的命
I have no interest in them.
我可没兴趣拿
The antidote is real.
解药是真的
Of course.
自然
Your target
你的目标
has always been me.
从始至终只有我一个
Let's get it all out
还有什么花样
in the open, shall we?
一块放出来吧
The poison on that porcelain bottle
那瓷瓶上的毒
is enough for you to enjoy for a while.
就够你好好享用一阵了
The toxin will
此毒会随着血液
spread through
在你周身游走
your bloodstream,
将毒带遍全身
paralyzing
然后
your whole body.
你的身体就会僵硬无比
Eventually,
最终
you'll become
你会变成一棵
a breathing tree.
会呼吸的树
You're quite a handful,
沈大阁领
aren't you?
还真是难缠
Why not
就这么安安静静地
just die
死在这里
quietly here?
不好吗
The true leader of the Fire Moth Sect,
火蛾门的总舵主
your real boss,
你真正的头目
is that person in the royal court.
是朝堂上那位吧
You use Chen Huo'e's identity
你们假借陈火蛾的身份
to create havoc, switching identities
到处装神弄鬼
and expanding your influence,
不停换身份扩张势力
not just to
不仅仅为的是
establish a base in Yingzhou
在营州建立一个火蛾门
but to covet all of Dacang.
而是觊觎整个大苍
You know,
沈大阁领
the more you know,
知道得越多
the faster you die.
死得越快
My mission this time is simple.
我此次的任务没有别的
Wipe out you, Shen Du,
就是一举歼灭
and your group.
你沈渡一行人
Now,
如今
you're already in my grasp.
你已是我的囊中之物
Who
不知
will be next, I wonder?
下一个会是谁呢
My Lord!
大阁领
Shen Du!
沈渡
Guess which one I'll pick one?
那我就自己选一个了
My Lord!
大阁领
Shen Du...
沈渡
He is poisoned by something strange.
大阁领恐是中了奇毒
Is there an antidote?
可有解
My medical skills are limited.
小的医术有限
I can't tell what poison it is.
看不出是何毒
The townsfolk got better
城中百姓服了大阁领
after taking the antidote
带回来的解药以后
Mr Shen brought back,
都有所好转
but he...
可偏偏大阁领他
These vile people
这帮害人精
keep coming up
没事就发明些
with bizarre poisons to harm others.
莫名其妙的毒药来害人
I swear,
我非端了
I'll destroy their base!
他们的老巢不可
Focus on saving lives first.
救人要紧
But I've already searched
可广春堂和莫府
Guangchun Hall and the Mo residence
我都已经翻遍了
from top to bottom,
都没有找到
nothing about any poisons.
有关毒药的东西
I'm one step away from turning over
我只差把火蛾门
every place
去过的地方
the Fire Moth Sect has ever been.
全部掀开来看了
Chen Huo'e is sly and cunning.
陈火蛾阴险狡诈
She wouldn't leave the antidote
自然是不会把毒的解法
out in the open.
放在明处
Is Mr Shen getting better?
大阁领好了
Acupuncture and sealing pressure points
针灸封穴
are just temporary measures.
只是暂缓之计
I haven't found
我现在也想不出来
another way
别的法子
to slow down
来减缓他
his body's stiffening.
躯体僵化的速度
If we don't find the antidote soon,
如果再找不到解药的话
I fear he...
恐怕他
The poison affecting Shen Du
沈渡中的毒
isn't one from the Central Plains.
不是中原的毒
I've translated books from the West.
我译过西域之书
The Fire Moth Sect's tricks
发现火蛾门的戏法
are strikingly similar
与金乌部落
to the sacred arts
传说中的圣门秘术
of the Jinwu Tribe legends.
极其相仿
Then we should go seek help from them.
那我们这就去求医问药
No.
不可
Years ago,
多年前
the Jinwu Tribe cut off
金乌部落突然断了
all contact with Dacang
和大苍的来往
and showed strong hostility
对大苍的人
toward its people.
表现得极为抗拒
If we rush in,
贸然前去
we might not save him
不但救不了他
and could end up
可能还会把我们
trapped there ourselves.
困在那儿
Then what should we do?
那怎么办
If I remember correctly,
要是没记错
I'm the one here
我们之中
most familiar with the Western Regions.
只有我最了解西域
I'll go and fetch the antidote.
我前去取解药便是
I'm going with you.
我也去
You need to stay here.
你得在这儿守着
Shen Du risked his life
沈渡拿自己的性命
to protect the people of Yingzhou.
守护了营州的百姓
You should stay and protect him.
你也该守护好他
And you must also
更应该替他
look after Mrs Shen.
照顾好沈夫人
Fortunately,
好在这里
the Jinwu Tribe isn't far from here.
离金乌部落并不远
Until I return,
在我回来之前
don't do anything stupid.
你们什么都别做
Thank you, Mr Pan.
多谢潘郎君
I'll repay this
大恩大德
great kindness one day.
来日再报
Take care.
路上注意安全
Wait for me.
等我回来
Hey there, traveler!
上客
I've got some good stuff on me.
我身上有好东西
Come take a look.
你瞧一瞧
Who are you?
什么人
I've got something good
跟你说有好东西
to share with you.
让你瞧上一眼
You Dacang people are really slippery.
大苍人果然狡猾
Shen Du,
沈渡
I've cooled it down for you.
我都给你吹凉了
Just take a sip, will you?
你喝一口呀
Last time, didn't you say
你上次不是跟我说
your shoulder was hurt
你肩膀扭伤了
and you couldn't drink on your own?
不能自己喝
You said you'd only drink if I fed you.
就要喝我给你喂的吗
Please, take one sip,
你起来喝一口好不好
just one sip.
就一口
Shen Du, get up.
沈渡你起来呀
Look at me, Shen Du.
你起来看看我啊 沈渡
I miss you.
我想你了
Has Mrs Shen
夫人这几日
still not eaten anything?
还是未曾进食
She's been right by his bedside,
她就一直守在床前
giving him acupuncture every hour.
每一个时辰施针一次
No matter what anyone says,
谁说什么都不肯休息
she won't rest or let anyone get close.
也不让别人靠近
If this keeps up,
再这样下去
she might collapse first.
没准夫人先倒下了
What do you think we should do now?
那你说现在可怎么办啊
If my calculations are right,
算日子
Mr Pan should be back
如果潘郎君顺利的话
from the Jinwu Tribe by now.
也该从金乌回来了
I'm just worried that before your lord
就怕你家大阁领的解药
gets the antidote,
还没到
Mrs Shen might collapse first.
姐姐先倒下了
Mrs Shen,
夫人
please take a break,
您歇息下吧
or at least eat something.
或者您吃点东西也行啊
If he wakes up and finds out
要是大阁领醒来
you've exhausted yourself,
发现您累倒了
he'll be heartbroken.
一定会很难过的
I won't collapse
他没醒过来之前
before he wakes up.
我是不会倒下的
Mr Pan is back!
潘郎君回来了
I was afraid if I didn't hurry back,
我怕我再不回来
you wouldn't hold on any longer.
你就坚持不住了
Did you find the antidote?
可有找到解药
This is...
这位是
Su Guang,
素光
the Holy Maiden of the Jinwu Tribe.
金乌部落的圣女
I told you
我是叫你
to bring him here quietly.
悄悄把人给请过来
Bring,
是请
not drag!
不是给扛过来
What happened?
怎么回事
He's extremely cunning.
他非常狡猾
I couldn't get him to come here nicely.
我根本就请不来
All right, all right,
行行行
just go. Go.
去吧去吧去吧
You're awake.
你醒了
It's you?
是你
It's the Ensnaring Vines.
是藤缠树
Do you know of this poison?
圣女可了解此毒
This poison
此毒
is mainly made from wood moth larvae,
是以木蠹蛾的幼虫为主
mixed with toxic plants
毒箭木
like Poison Arrowwood,
百日草
Centenarian Flower,
西域乌头等
and Western Monkshood.
带毒的植株为辅
Who would've thought a tiny moth
没想到这种小蛾
could make such a strong poison?
竟能研制出如此烈毒
But this is a secret technique
但此毒是只有我族圣女
only known to our Holy Maidens.
才知晓的制毒秘法
It's never shared with outsiders.
从不外传啊
Then, how did
既不外传
the leader of the Fire Moth Sect
那为何火蛾门的主上
get hands on such a hidden poison?
会有这隐世的毒药
Could there be more to this?
难道此事有隐情
Let me make it brief.
我长话短说吧
It's banned by our tribe
因此毒太过于阴毒
for being too malicious.
早被我族禁用
However, many years ago,
但多年以前
one of our Maidens disappeared,
我族的一位圣女失踪了
and she's never heard from again.
此后再无音信
So, it's possible that
这么说来
the Maiden was
这位圣女
linked to the Fire Moth Sect
可能跟火蛾门有联系
and shared this poison recipe.
将此毒传授
Impossible!
不会的
That's Dai Si.
圣女黛丝
She would never collude with a cult.
一定不会与邪教勾结
You're the Holy Maiden.
你是圣女
You must have the antidote,
一定会有救人的解药
right?
对不对
Before I came,
来之前
I heard a bit about this from Pan Chi.
我听潘驰讲了个大致
I searched through our texts
我又翻阅书籍
and made a special antidote.
特调制此药
I hope it works.
但愿能有效果吧
I'm deeply grateful
今日解药之恩
for this antidote today.
感激不尽
You saved my life once,
你救过我的命
and I promised to come with you.
我答应随你来一趟
But remember, this antidote
但此药得另算
comes with its own price.
别忘了你答应我的事
A gentleman's word
君子一言
is his bond.
驷马难追
Mr Pan sure has a way with people,
这潘郎君可以啊
even making romantic debts in the West.
风流债都欠到西域去了
Shen Du?
沈渡
Shen Du, you're awake?
沈渡你醒了
How do you feel?
怎么样啊 现在
Any discomfort?
还有哪里不舒服吗
Easy, slow down.
你慢点慢点慢点
After sleeping for so long,
睡了这么久
I've kind of missed you.
都有点想你了
If you dare
你要是再敢
scare me like this again,
这么欺负我的话
I'll ignore you forever.
我就再也不理你了
It won't happen again.
下次不会了
He's awake?
大阁领醒了
Hey, kid!
你这小屁孩
Some things aren't for you to see!
不该看的东西不能看
Call me a kid one more time,
你再叫我小孩
and I'll get mad.
我可生气了
What?
不服
Wanna duel?
咱俩决斗
Kid.
小孩
Heaven watched over us to survive this.
苍天保佑 化险为夷
What's with you, kid?
你这小孩怎么回事
Didn't I tell you
我不是告诉你
not to look at things
不该看的东西
you shouldn't?
不能看 不能看
Why don't you listen?
你怎么那么不懂事
Shen Du,
沈渡
I really missed you.
我真的好想你
Seems like
看来
you've put your heart into it after all.
你还是用真心了
You've been unconscious for days.
你昏睡数日
It's best not to drink too much tea.
不宜饮过多茶饮
Give me your hand.
把手给我
Your pulse is steady.
脉象平稳
Most of the poison has been cleared.
看来毒已解得差不多了
If you need anything, just say it,
你有什么事你就直言
whether it's food
是要用膳
or a bath and a change of clothes.
还是要沐浴更衣
Don't move.
别动
Do you feel any discomfort?
可有不适
As for the situation in Yingzhou,
营州的事
I've asked Jing Lin to watch it.
我让景林盯着呢
Sun Tan and the Delinquent
城中有孙谭
are maintaining order in the city.
带着异良人维持秩序
This will all
这件事
be over soon.
很快会结束的
What about the remaining Fire Moth Sect?
那火蛾门的余孽呢
I've told Jing Lin to keep the news
我让景林封锁了
of my recovery under wraps.
我毒已经解的消息
Do you think they'll believe it?
他们真的会信吗
The point is to keep them uncertain.
要的就是他们不敢确信
What news have you gathered?
打探的消息如何了
My Lord,
回主上
there's talk all over the city
现在城里都在传
that the White Death from the capital
那位京城来的
is on his last breath.
白无常快死了
And his wife,
而他夫人
before he's even passed,
竟还没等夫君咽气
has already cozied up
就跟那位神探潘驰
to that detective, Pan Chi.
勾搭在了一起
I heard Mrs Shen
听说沈渡的夫人
and Pan Chi go way back.
与潘驰是旧相识
There's always been something fishy.
本就不清不楚
A woman's heart is deadlier
黄蜂尾上针
than a wasp's sting.
最毒妇人心
The camp was destroyed by soldiers,
营地虽然被官兵捣毁
but if Shen Du died,
可只要沈渡一死
chaos would surely follow.
势必会乱作一团
The entire city of Yingzhou
到时候整个营州城
will be yours for the taking.
便是主上的囊中之物了
Just in case it's a trap,
以防有诈
investigate further.
再探
Yes!
是
Is this cinnabar?
是丹砂
Yes, it fell off Chen Huo'e
这是那日打斗时
during the fight that day.
陈火蛾身上掉下来的
I had Jing Lin
我让景林
search Guangchun Hall again,
再次搜索了广春堂
and they found traces
果然在角落里
of cinnabar scattered in a corner.
找到了遗落的细碎丹砂
Cinnabar is common in alchemy,
丹砂常被炼丹所用
but it's very rare,
产量极少
and worth a fortune.
故而十分珍贵
Ten gold for a peck is fair.
一斗十金也不为过
Where did they get it?
火蛾门怎么会有
If taken in small doses over time,
若是让人少量长期服用
it can act as a preservative,
也就是会提前防腐
which is why their bodies
所以死后
don't decompose after death.
尸体才能长时间不腐
So,
原来
they've been preparing
火蛾门一早
this technique for their followers
就准备了给教徒
to come back from the dead all along.
这死而复生的技法
The extraction of cinnabar
丹砂的开采
is tightly controlled by the court,
严格掌控在朝廷手里
yet the Fire Moth Sect
火蛾门却能轻易地
has it in abundance.
大量拥有
It looks like they've infiltrated
看来他们早就渗入了
Dacang's mining operations.
大苍的矿业
Their ambition is far greater
野心之大
than we imagined.
远超想象
Are you saying...
你的意思是
the one behind
难不成
the Fire Moth Sect
这火蛾门的幕后之人
is planning to...
是想要
Cry!
哭
Cry for what?
哭什么
I can't do it.
哭不出来
I've been waiting for you all.
等你们很久了
You should try switching up
你的迷魂香
your Mindbender Mist.
也该换换花样了
So, you really are alive.
你果真还活着
Did you think I was made of paper?
你真当本阁领是纸糊的
You're not Chen Huo'e.
你不是陈火蛾
Can't you
你的真面目
show your real face?
就这么不能示人吗
Have you really figured it all out,
你真的看透了吗
Shen Du?
沈渡
My Lord,
大阁领
she escaped.
让她逃了
Keep an eye on them.
看好他们
I want them alive.
我要活口
Yes!
是
There's actually a way to
竟会有令物品
make something burn up that quickly?
如此快速燃尽的方法
It happened so suddenly,
事发突然
and there was so much smoke at the time.
当时烟雾太大
All I could smell was a sharp,
我只闻到了一股
acrid scent.
刺鼻的味道
What are you thinking about?
你在想什么
Remember the Holy Maiden Dai Si
你记得我跟你提过的
I mentioned before?
圣女黛丝吗
Rumor has it
传闻中
she developed a technique that
她曾经研发过一种
accelerates burning.
助燃术
Not just a wall,
不要说是这面墙了
this entire courtyard
即便是这整个院子
could be reduced to ashes
都能在片刻之内
in an instant.
被燃烧殆尽
My Lord,
大阁领
we've found a witness
找到了当年粮仓大火的
from the granary fire years ago.
一名目击者
He smelt
据他所说
an extremely
当时在周围
pungent odor
闻到了一股
at the scene,
极其刺鼻的味道
and thought that
而且那场大火
the fire was quite strange.
看上去十分诡异
It's surrounded by purple flares.
竟不时地冒出紫光
The Flame Accelerant Technique.
金乌助燃术
If used on a granary,
若用此术烧粮仓
it'd burn down in half a day.
的确无需半日
So,
如此说来
Holy Maiden Dai Si
金乌部落的黛丝圣女
is likely connected
看来是与火蛾门
to the Fire Moth Sect.
脱不了干系
What do you mean?
什么意思
Su Guang, why are you here?
素光圣女来此是何目的
Even though Dacang rarely has dealings
我大苍虽然与金乌部落
with the Jinwu Tribe,
鲜有往来
we know the disappearance of
但也知道圣女失踪
your Holy Maiden was a big deal.
乃是大事
How calm you are!
如此平静
It's likely there was a plan all along.
怕不是早有预谋吧
I didn't intend to hide anything.
我并非是有意隐瞒
Dai Si
圣女黛丝
eloped with a man from Dacang
与一大苍男子私奔
and disappeared without a trace.
从此以后下落不明
The chieftain wanted to keep it quiet.
族长本想着息事宁人
But in recent years,
不想这想年
techniques and formulas
竟多次出现
known only to our Maidens
仅本族圣女知晓的
have surfaced multiple times.
幻术技法和方剂
I thought
我想着
we must find out the truth quickly
必须要尽快查明真相
to prevent any unforeseen trouble.
以免圣门遭无妄之灾
A man from Dacang?
大苍男子
Jing Lin.
景林
My Lord.
大阁领
Report to the capital.
派人快马回京呈报
The crisis in Yingzhou is resolved.
营州危机已解
Yes.
是
You've been pacing outside for ages.
在外面转了这么久
Finally decided to come in?
总算是进来了
Not exactly playing the guest, are you?
还真是不客气
There's something I wanna say,
有一句话
but I'm not sure if it's the right time.
不知道当讲不当讲
If not,
不当讲的话
then keep quiet.
那就别讲
Stick to your promise
我劝你早日兑现约定
and divorce Yan Xing.
与颜幸和离
But who exactly are you
你现在是以什么身份
to tell me this?
同我说话
A friend dressed up
一个装扮成女子的
as a woman?
杵臼好友吗
Just a couple in name only.
不过是名义上的夫妻
As the mighty lord,
堂堂大阁领
you seem awfully confident.
还真是有底气
Some things
有些话
are better left unsaid.
说出口还是小心为好啊
How will you make she happy when
每天在刀尖上的白无常
you live on the edge as White Death?
你该如何给颜幸幸福呢
My wife's well-being
本阁领夫人的安危
isn't
好像不劳烦
your concern.
潘郎君费心吧
As long as I'm around,
只要有我沈渡在一日
no one will lay a finger on her.
没人伤得了颜幸
You've got
这大阁领
quite the ego.
还真是嚣张跋扈啊
I wonder
也真不知道
what she sees in you.
颜幸看上你什么了
Fine,
好啊
since you've made your point,
今日既然你已经说了
make sure you stand by it.
那就请你说到做到
If not...
不然的话
If not, what?
要不然如何
find her
就算是天涯海角
and take her away,
我也一定会回来
no matter where she is.
把她带走
You've seen how close
我们夫妻之间的情感
Yan Xing
你应该已经
and I are.
看得很清楚了
Let me make this clear.
今日我便把话放在这儿
That day will never come.
你等不到那一天
You'd better hope so.
最好
Are you leaving with the Holy Maiden?
是要跟圣女走了吗
Aren't you just as curious
你不是也对
about what happened
那个黛丝圣女的去向
to Dai Si?
很感兴趣吗
She's not just anyone.
圣女身份尊贵
You'd better make sure she's safe.
可得护卫好了
Such a shame
多好一杯子
to break a perfectly good cup.
就这么打烂了
What a waste.
可惜了
What a fool.
鲁莽啊
Thanks to you risking your life
多亏你冒死
to get the antidote from Chen Huo'e,
从陈火蛾手中护下解药
the townspeople
城里中毒的百姓
who were poisoned
服下之后
have all recovered quickly.
很快就都恢复了
Seeing them healthy
看着百姓恢复
and back to their peaceful lives,
过上了安稳的生活
it makes
我就觉得
all the hard work
就算办案再辛苦
worth it.
都值得
Mr Shen.
大阁领
thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you so much
谢谢大阁领
for saving me
谢谢你救了我
and all the people
谢谢你救了
of Yingzhou.
整个营州城的百姓
You're a good official.
您是个好官
This is just a little something from us.
这些是我们一点心意
Please,
您别嫌弃
don't refuse it.
您收下
Thank you
大阁领
for saving our lives.
谢谢大阁领的救命之恩
Thank you.
谢谢
This is a small token of our gratitude.
这是一点心意
My Lord,
大阁领
this is a little gift from me.
这是我的一点心意
Please, you must accept it.
你一定要收下呀
Thank you, sir.
谢谢大阁领
Thank you for saving our lives.
谢谢大阁领的救命之恩
Mr Shen is truly a good man!
大阁领可真是个好官啊
We will never
我们一辈子
forget
也忘不了
your kindness.
您的大恩大德呀
Yes, thank you.
对 谢谢大阁领
Thank you, thank you!
谢谢大阁领
You're all too kind.
你们真的太客气了
This is what he's
这都是我们大阁领
supposed to do.
应该做的
Really, there's no need.
不用不用
Please, don't say that.
您别这么说 真的
We insist.
别嫌弃
-Please don't refuse. -Just take it.
别嫌弃就好 别嫌弃
Thank you, my lord.
谢谢大阁领 谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢大阁领
Mr Shen is such a good man!
大阁领真是好官啊
Quit smiling.
还笑
Help me hold some of these.
帮我拿着点
These are all gifts for you.
这可都是他们给你的
You should be the one
这满满的心意
to carry them.
当然要大阁领
It's their heartfelt gratitude for you.
你自己拿着了
You should
我看你以后
spend less time with Pan Chi.
还是跟潘驰少打交道
You'll pick up his rebellious streak.
免得学了他一身反骨
and silver tongue.
巧言利口
He didn't even
他走之前
say goodbye before leaving.
都没有来打招呼
He must've gotten on your nerves.
看来是去招惹了你
The connection between
黛丝圣女
Dai Si and the Fire Moth Sect
和火蛾门是何关系
is no small matter.
事关重大
I have a feeling
我倒觉得
he had other intentions for his trip.
他此行定另有目的
Even better.
那反倒好啊
If he dares make a move
要是再敢觊觎
on someone else's wife again,
别人家的夫人
I'll break his legs.
当心我打断他的腿
Is my lady embarrassed?
夫人害羞了
People are watching.
还有人呢
I'm cold.
冷
How about now?
现在呢
Come a little closer.
你再往前靠点
I'm holding something here.
我手上拿着东西呢
Closer...
往前靠点
I'm cold.
冷
Really.
真的冷
You better not tease me again.
你以后不准再戏弄于我
Much warmer now.
现在暖和多了
Shen Du,
沈渡
it's snowing! Come outside!
下雪了 快出来